James D. Kim

- Diamond Bar, CA CELL (909) 342-0400 E-MAIL bronze10000@gmail.com
- PORTFOLIO https://bronze10000.github.io/portfolio/

PROFILE

As a full-stack web developer with a background in research and eCommerce, I bring my love of learning and an analytical mindset honed from conducting experiments on a lab bench. My ultimate goal is to write awesome code as I continually improve my craft as a web developer.

EDUCATION Web

Web Development Immersive

General Assembly

1933 S. Broadway, Los Angeles, CA 90007

B.S. in Botany

University of California, Davis 1 Shields Ave, Davis, CA 95616

.....

SKILLS

HTML & CSS Javascript Ruby Liquid Ruby on Rails Bootstrap MongoDB MySQL JQuery Git ZenCart Wordpress Shopify SEO Ecommerce Ebay

SASS WooCommerce

EXPERIENCE

Web developer at BNJ Abrasives

Nov., 2017 - current

- Creat & heavily modify company Wordpress website (Javascript, JQuery, PHP, HTML, CSS)
- Search Engine Optimization of company web presence
- Convert to Woocommerce for e-commerce functionality
 - Utilize 3rd party plugins for logistics
 - USPS and UPS plugins were optimized for usability

Contract web developer at The Joy Factory

Nov., 2016-Nov., 2017

- Heavily modify company Shopify website (Liquid, Javascript, JQuery, HTML, CSS)
- Modify company microsite (HTML, CSS, Bootstrap)
- Search Engine Optimization of company web presence
- Integrate 3rd party apps with Shopify platform
- Use JQuery to create landing page animations

Web developer at Pac Com International

Aug., 2016 - Nov., 2016

- Create & heavily modify company Wordpress website (Javascript, JQuery, HTML, CSS)
- Search Engine Optimization of company web presence
- Integrate 3rd party apps with Wordpress platform
- Use JQuery to create additional styling

Freelance web developer

since April, 2014

Develop Wordpress websites

- Develop Zencart websites
- Develop Shopify websites
 - o Use Slate to upload/push theme to Shopify account
- Develop WooCommerce websites

Tutor

Spring, 2015 - current

- Teach bioinformatics
- Explain current research in caloric restriction of yeast
- Use R Packages to conduct bioinformatics research using available datasets
- Use REST API (MyGene.info) to pull data for webpage population

Researcher Spring, 2012-2014

• Studied role of Ecdysone Receptor, isoform A, in Aedes aegypti mosquito

Research Specialist

2005-2012(Spring)

• Studied G-protein signaling in filamentous fungus, Neurospora crassa

Research Associate 1994-2002

• Plant Pathology department of Seminis Vegetable Seeds, Co.

REFERENCES Available upon request